Balogun Razak

• Lagos, Nigeria

y @razak2free

in Balogun Razak

+234 810 321 8560

razakdev.com

7 razak1104

🖹 Balogun Razak



Profile

I am an astute Software Engineer (Frontend) with 4+ years of professional experience building responsive websites and web application designs from concept through to deployment helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. I can highly adapt to a continuous learning environment and am eager to tackle complex problems which maximize productivity.

Skills

Manual Testing	••••	JavaScript	••••
React Js	••••	TypeScript	• • • • •
React-Redux	••••	Apollo Graphql	• • • •
Next JS	••••	Version Control Git	• • • • •
AWS	••••	Node JS	• • • • •
CSS & CSS Framworks	••••	Mongo DB	••••

Education

Lagos, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science, Lagos State University *⊘*

Professional Experience

09/2021 – present Lagos, Nigeria **React Frontend Developer,** *Econnect Netpower Limited ⊗* **UI Designing & Application Interface Development**

- Analyzed user requirements and developed 30+ responsive and functional UI components via REACT concepts
- Built the application interface code using **JavaScript and React.js** based on the pre-made designs and wireframes

Code Testing & Debugging

- Troubleshoot and debugged 10+ applications' code for smooth execution and improved stability
- Developed and Tested front-end architecture along with the UI concepts of 10+ websites to perform with 100% accuracy

07/2018 – 01/2019 Lagos, Nigeria

Web Developer Intern, Compact Technologies

- Assisted in the development of user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks.
- Troubleshoot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Utilized scripting languages to design websites under the supervision of the lead developer.

08/2019 – 07/2021 Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Developer, Fulus Investment Limited

- Develop high-performance customer-facing e-commerce applications using React.JS, Redux-saga, React Hooks, React-Router, and TypeScript.
- Developed a custom API layer to handle all CRUD transactions, and JSON Web Token management and implemented interceptors to embed custom headers
- Used Middleware, Redux-Saga with Immutable in application to retrieve and store data from Back-End and to also perform RESTFUL services
- Expertise in using **GitLab** and **Jira** as version control and tracking units.